Guide to the Food and recipe booklets collection, 1864-1976.
Food and recipe booklets collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Food and recipe booklets, 1864-1976.
8006
1.7 cubic ft.
Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Booklets relating to food and cooking.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Booklets relating to food and cooking.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Cooking,American--History.; Formulas, recipes, etc.--United States--History.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian participation.; World War II.; Cooking (Gelatin).; Food conservation.
Form and Genre Terms:
Recipes.; Cookbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Related material in collection #8568, Diane Scrima Collection of Recipe Booklets and Cookbooks.
CONTAINER LIST
- Food and Recipe Booklets ca. 1880s-1970s
- Appliances (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Arrow Publishing (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Baking Powder-included Rumford (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bread, including Fleischmann's (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Canning (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Center for Service in Public Interest (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cheese (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Corn (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cutlery (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Desserts (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Fish and Shellfish (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Flour (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Food porn (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Fondue (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Frozen Foods (Box 1, Folder 17)
- General Electric (Box 1, Folder 18)
- General Foods Corporation (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Grange League Federation (GLF) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Great Atlantic Lobster Co. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Holiday (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Home Canning Supplies (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Home Economics Bulletins (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Home Economics Recipes (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Hunger (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Insurance- Metropolitan Life (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Jams & Jellies (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Gelatin-Jello, Knox, Larkin (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Kitchen Equipment (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Knudsen (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Lard (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Management (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Margarine (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Marketing (Box 2, Folder 14)
- McCall's Recipes (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Meat (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Milk-evaporated and Nestle's (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Mustard (Box 2, Folder 18)
- National Dairy Council (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Oil-Weson (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Orange Juice-Sunkist (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Outdoor (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Party food and beverages (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Quaker Oats (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Quality Bakers of America (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Recipes/Recipe Cards (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Recipes/Recipe Card - including Kate Smith's Favorite Recipes (1939) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Recipes/Recipe Card - including Kate Smith's Favorite Recipes (1939) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Reynolds Wrap (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Salads (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Sandwiches (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Sauerkraut (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Soap (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Soap (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Stainless Steel (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Sucaryl-non-caloric sweetner (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Tobacco (Box 3, Folder 11)
- USDA (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Walnuts (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Westinghouse - Home Freeze Guide, 1968 (Box 5)
- Yankee Books (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 4-H Dairy Foods Project Manual (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Rice Council - Great Dinners for Six (Box 3, Folder 16)
- California Raisin Brochure (Box 3, Folder 17)
- American Egg Board (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Brochures for Corn Syrup, Mazola Oil, Hellmann's Mayo, Skippy Peanut Butter (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Soy (Box 3, Folder 20)
- "Food of Our Fathers" - Institute of Food Technologists (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Kraft - "Outsmarting the Cash Register" (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Handwritten recipe book, Blank book with printed title "Recipes: my friends' and my own," copyright 1900, with recipes written in by hand or glued in as newspaper clippings. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Handwritten recipe book, Untitled recipe book, with signature MRN, 1860 on front pastedown. Mostly cake recipes, together with some for vegetables (such as pickled cabbage), soda water, etc. Poor condition, fragile binding, pages stained. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Loose recipes (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous-not recipes (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Commercial recipe booklets-Karo Cook Book by Emma Churchman Hewitt; "Superior Salads," from Duffy's Apple Juice Vinegar; "Directions for Operating 'Lorain' Oven Heat Regulator," American Stove Company; Book of Formulas for Preparing of Syrups, Etc.," Crown Cordial and Extract Company; "The Celebrated Vienna Pressed Yeast", undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "Just a Cook Book for Economical Gas Cooking," American Stove Company, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "100 Ways to Better Health," Battle Creek Food Company, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Mrs. Winslow's Domestic Receipt Book, 1872;1875 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Ransom's Family Receipt Book, 1876;1879;1884 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Ladies Note-Book and Calendar, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Choice Receipts by Maria Parloa, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- National Yeast Company, Seneca Falls, no date (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Housekeeper's Receipt Book, Carter's Compound Extract of Smart Weed, no date (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Hyde's Practical Miscellaneous Recipe Book, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "The Practical Cookbook," by Mrs. H. M. Robinson, New York: Abbey and Barrett, 1864 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- The American Domestic Cook Book, 1869-1870 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- "Choice Gleanings," Columbus Avenue Church, Boston, MA., 1883 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Tompkins County Old Time Recipes and Philosophy of Housekeeping," Cornell University, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Money-Saving Main Dishes, USDA and "Hot from the Oven," cookie recipes compiled by Elinor Genung Allen, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Family Fare: Food Management and Recipes, USDA, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Handwritten recipe books (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
- "Cooking with Imagination for Special Diets" (Box 4, Folder 12)
- "Holiday Meals For Wartime", by Mary Lee Taylor (Box 5)
- "Drinking and Dining Recipes from the Original Thirteen Colonies", by Lord Calvert Whiskey Company (Box 5)
- "The History of the Spoon, Knife and Fork", by Reed and Barton, 1926 (Box 5)
- "The History of Spices" by American Spice Trade Association, 1960 (Box 5)
- "A Handbook on the Jewish Dietary Laws", 1954 (Box 5)
- "Ways with Wine" Paul Masson Vineyards, 1968 (Box 5)
- "Thoughts for Teas" by Saga Food Service (Box 5)
- Notebook with clippings of World War I recipes, especially for meatless and wheatless meals (Box 5)
- "From Tree to Table", Curtice Brothers Company, Preservers, Rochester, New York, 1893 (Box 5)
- D.M. Osborne and Company, "Handy Book for House and Farm", no date (Box 5)
- "Apples for You!", Alice L. Spencer (Recipes) and E. Stuart Hubbard (Horticulturalist), no date (Box 5)
- "Campfire Girl (CFG) Campfire Cookery", no date (Box 5)
- "Trail Cookery for Girl Scouts", no date (Box 5)
- "Trail Cookery for Girl Scouts", by the Home Economics Dept., Kellogg Company, Battle Creek, Michigan, no date (Box 5)
- "A Manual of Cooking for Boy Scouts", by the Home Economics Dept., Kellogg Company, Battle Creek, Michigan, no date (Box 5)
- "Cheese", by Luella Sherman Mortensen and Beulah V. Gillaspie (McCall's Magazine), no date (Box 5)
- "Summer Cook Book", by Good Housekeeping, no date (Box 5)
- "Canned Salmon Delicacies", by Lola M. Cremeans (University of Alaska), 1937 (Box 5)
- "Health-for-Victory Club Meal Planning Guide / Early Summer Home Canning: What to Can ... How to Do It", by Home Economics Institute, 1943 (Box 5)
- "Perfect Pies and How to Make Them", by National Household Service and The Proctor and Gamble Co., 1928 (Box 5)
- "Wonder Sandwich Suggestions", by Alice Adams Proctor, 1930 (Box 5)
- "Spring Suggestions, Including Lenten Recipes", by The Food Education Bureau, no date (Box 5)
- "When You Entertain: A Woman's Home Companion Booklet", 1933 (Box 5)
- "Your War Garden for 1944: Helpful Information from Firestone Farm and Garden Service Bureau", 1944 (Box 5)
- "Food and Health", by Lydia E. Pinkham Medicine Co., no date (Box 5)
- "Cook with Milk", by the Extension Service of the College of Agriculture, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1931 (Box 5)
- "Ways to Use Wisconsin Apples", by the Extension Service of the College of Agriculture, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1931 (Box 5)
- "Rumford Cook Book", by Fannie Merritt Farmer (and the Rumford Chemical Works), no date (Box 5)
- "Everyday Uses for Cherries", by Luella Mortenson, no date (Box 5)
- "Bananas Take a Bow ... in Attractive New Dishes for the Up-to-Date Hostess", no date (Box 5)
- "Banana Salad Bazaar", by the Home Economics Dept., Fruit Dispatch Co., no date (Box 5)
- "Quick-Quick-Quick 16 Smackin'-Good Meal Ideas with the New Minute Rice", by General Foods Corp., 1949 (Box 5)
- "What Shall I Cook Today? 124 Thrifty, Healthful Tested Recipes" with Spry (Pure Vegetable Shortening), by the Lever Brothers Co., no date (Box 5)
- "Magic Short-Cut Recipes for the Automatic Refrigerator", no date (Box 5)
- "Minute Cook Book", by the Minute Tapioca Co., Orange, Mass., 1915 (Box 5)
- "Menu Magic", by the National Biscuit Company, 1932 (Box 5)
- "Eggs: 100 Tempting Ways to Serve Them", by the New England Fresh Egg Institute, Worcester, Mass., no date (Box 5)
- Milk Recipes by H. P. Hood and Sons, no date (Box 5)
- "Recipes for Today", by General Foods Corp., 1943 (Box 5)
- "Tested Recipes: Successful Baking for Flavor and Texture", by Martha Lee Anderson, 1936 (Box 5)
- "The Right Food for Your Family", by the Vermont State Nutrition Committee and the Maltex Company, no date (Box 5)
- "What to Eat and Why", by Alice F. Blood, 1939 (Box 5)
- "Atlas Book of Recipes and Helpful Information about Canning", no date (Box 5)
- "The Sunny Side of Life Book", by the Kellogg Company, Battle Creek, Michigan, 1934 (Box 5)
- "A New Way of Living: Come Over to the Sunny Side of Life", by the Kellogg Company, Battle Creek, Michigan, 1932 (Box 5)
- "Nutrition: Important Flashes of Nutrition News", by the Quaker Oats Company, 1938-1940 (Box 5)
  (Vol. 1, No. 3-5; Vol. 2, No. 9; Vol. 3, No. 1)
- "The Student Home Economist: A National Newspaper for Home Economics Students", 1938 (Box 5)
  (Vol. 1, No. 1)
- "Household Nutrition: A Timely and Reliable Clip-Sheet for the Women", 1931 (Box 5)
  (July 25 and "Spring Issue")
- "Wonderful Ways with Soups from Campbells", 1958 (Box 5)
- "Plain and Fancy Gravy Dishes" Campbell Soup Company, Undated (Box 5)
- Campbell's Red Kettle Soup Mix Recipes, Undated (Box 5)
- "50 Classic Bean Dishes" Campbell Soup Company, Undated (Box 5)
- "It's Home From Work We Go" Campbell Soup Company, Undated (Box 5)